A Finding Aid to the Paul Bransom Papers, 1862-1985 bulk 1904-1979, in the Archives of American Art AAA.branpaul
Archives of American Art
- Correspondence, circa 1903-1984; Series 2; 4.5 Linear feet Box 1-5
  - General Correspondence, 1979; (2 folders) (Box 4, Folder 6-7)
  - General Correspondence, 1980-1982 (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - General Correspondence, 1983-1984 (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - General Correspondence, A-B, undated (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - General Correspondence, C-F, undated (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - General Correspondence, G-H, undated (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - General Correspondence, I-L, undated (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - General Correspondence, M, undated (Box 4, Folder 14)
  - General Correspondence, N-R, undated (Box 4, Folder 15)
  - General Correspondence, S-Y, undated (Box 4, Folder 16)
  - General Correspondence, First Names Only, undated; (2 folders) (Box 4, Folder 17-18)
  - Drafts of Letters by Paul Bransom, undated (Box 4, Folder 19)
  - Cards (Box 4)
    - Paul Bransom's Outgoing Christmas Cards, circa 1930, 1963-1965, undated; (2 folders, including duplicates) (Box 4, Folder 20-21)
    - Wendy Astley-Bell, 1966, undated (Box 4, Folder 22)
      (Contains original artwork)
    - Alice Atkinson, undated (Box 4, Folder 23)
    - Miscellaneous A, 1955-1968, undated (Box 4, Folder 24)
    - Wladislaw, Romola, and Emilia Benda, undated (Box 4, Folder 25)
    - Miscellaneous B, 1953-1978, undated; (2 folders) (Box 4, Folder 26-27)
      (Contains cards made by Harry Beckhoff, Frank Bensing, Ed Bierly, Walter Biggs, Pat Bott, Bob Brikerhoff, and Joseph Burgess)
    - Chen Chi, undated; (2 folders, including duplicates) (Box 4, Folder 28-29)
    - Miscellaneous C, 1956-1979, undated; (2 folders) (Box 4, Folder 30-31)
      (Contains cards made by Harrison Cady, Bob Carroll, Charles Chapman, John Clymer, Kent Day Coes, Farrell Collett, Elizabeth Cowan, and a photograph of John Clymer)
    - Gerard Curtis Delano, undated (Box 4, Folder 32)
    - Rita Duis (Astley-Bell), 1971-1980, undated (Box 4, Folder 33)
    - Miscellaneous D, 1961-1968, undated (Box 4, Folder 34)
      (Contains cards made by Bob Davenport, Joe Davis, Gladdys Davis, and Charles DeFeo)
    - Miscellaneous E, 1950-1977, undated (Box 4, Folder 35)
      (Contains cards made by Rosalie Edge)
    - Miscellaneous F, 1963-1967, undated (Box 4, Folder 36)
      (Contains cards made by Bill Freeman, O.E. von Feuher, and Elisabeth Fulda)
    - Miscellaneous G, 1957-1977, undated (Box 4, Folder 37)
      (Contains cards mdae by Rube Goldberg, Frank Gervasi, and Al Gilbert)
    - Malthe Hasselriis, undated (Box 4, Folder 38)
    - Miscellaneous H, 1954-1974, undated (Box 4, Folder 39-40)
      (Contains cards made by Grant Hagen, Charles Hargens, John Hamburger, Helen Ireland Hays, Lynn Bogue Hunt, and photographs of Frank and Brownie Hibben)
    - Miscellaneous I-J, undated (Box 4, Folder 41)
      (Contains cards made by Helen Ingliss, Joseph C. Jones, Anders Jordahl, and Hazel Brill Jackson)
    - Bob and Dorie Kane, undated (Box 4, Folder 42)
    - Bob Kuhn, 1963-1974, undated (Box 4, Folder 43)
    - Walt Kuhn, 1940, undated (Box 4, Folder 44)
    - Miscellaneous K, 1977-1978, undated (Box 5, Folder 1)
      (Contains cards made by Phil Kappel, Isabelle Knobloch, and Les Kouba)
    - Miscellaneous L, 1959-1981, undated (Box 5, Folder 2-3)
      (Contains cards made by Jack Lehrer, Dorothy Lathrop, William R. Leigh, Kay Lichty, and an original drawing by Bob Lougheed)
    - Ugo and Edna Mochi, 1974-1980, undated (Box 5, Folder 4)
    - Benson Moore, 1969, undated; (2 folders, including duplicates) (Box 5, Folder 5-6)
    - Miscellaneous M, 1962-1980, undated (Box 5, Folder 7-8)
      (Contains cards made by Joseph Margulies, Dorcas MacClintock, Don Miller, and Olaus Murie)
    - Miscellaneous N, 1981, undated (Box 5, Folder 9)
      (Contains cards made by A. Henry Nordhausen)
    - Tom Olenchak, undated (Box 5, Folder 10)
    - Miscellaneous O-R, 1967-1968, undated (Box 5, Folder 11)
      (Contains cards made by Karl Plath and O. Plancy)
    - Charles Sarka, 1938, 1957, undated (Box 5, Folder 12)
    - William Schaldach, undated (Box 5, Folder 13)
    - Conrad Schwiering, undated (Box 5, Folder 14)
    - Bob Scriver, 1970, undated (Box 5, Folder 15)
    - Alexander Seidel, undated (Box 5, Folder 16)
    - Bob Sleicher, undated (Box 5, Folder 17)
    - The Streeters, 1958-1978, undated (Box 5, Folder 18)
    - Tom Suggs, undated (Box 5, Folder 19)
    - Miscellaneous S, 1967-1978, undated (Box 5, Folder 20-21)
      (Contains cards made by Lloyd Sandford, Tona Soglow, Ben Stahl, the Spiro's, and Dolf Swing)
    - Kilpurdy Tee-Van, 1965-1966, undated (Box 5, Folder 22)
    - Clarence Tillenius, undated (Box 5, Folder 23)
    - Wayne Trimm, undated (Box 5, Folder 24)
    - Miscellaneous T, 1932, undated (Box 5, Folder 25)
      (Contains cards made by Don Teague, Anice and Albert Payson Terhune, and Ed Tomasieriez)
    - Wheeler Williams, undated (Box 5, Folder 26)
    - James Perry Wilson, 1957-1974 (Box 5, Folder 27)
    - Miscellaneous V-Z, 1955-1975, undated (Box 5, Folder 28-29)
      (Contains cards made by Pietro Valerio, Vilma and F. Warren, Ernest Watson, Katherine Lane Weems, Grant Hagen, and William Zimmerman)
    - Miscellaneous First Names Only, 1962-1978, undated (Box 5, Folder 30-32)
- Notes and Writings, circa 1927-1973; Series 3; 0.2 Linear feet Box 5, OV 12
  This small series includes a diary, notebooks, essays, lists, notes, and other writings by Paul Bransom and others. The diary, with notes, writings, and sketches, was written during a hunting expedition Bransom made with writer J. Frank Dobie in 1927. Other writings in this folder include an eight page essay recounting the hunt by G.W. "Dub" Evans. Four notebooks contain miscellaneous notes on travel expenses, contact information, drafts of outgoing letters, and pressed flowers. Biographical, historical, nature, and art writings include brief essays and notes for talks by Bransom and others about his career, the lives of fellow artists, animals and animal art, and a satirical essay about modern art. Notes by and about Walt Kuhn include an essay by Bransom, comments by Bransom on a journal article about Kuhn, and a sketchbook with visual notes made by Kuhn during a discussion with Paul and Grace Bransom.
  Notes on animals and artwork include research notes, ideas for illustrations and stories, and technical notes about artwork. Also found are lists of private collectors of Bransom's work and notes on members of the Jackson Hole, Wyoming, community. Miscellaneous notes concern books, music, spiritual musings, inspirational quotes from published sources, and notes related to items in this collection which have become separated from those items. A folder of poems inspired by Bransom and his paintings, many of which were written by friends for Bransom's birthday, is also present, as well as a photocopy of an inventory from an unknown repository of papers related to H.C. Pitz.
  Additional biographical notes and writings concerning Bransom and his career can be found in Biographical Materials. Additional notes pertaining to professional projects and financial matters can be found in Personal Business Records.
  - Diary and Other Writings, New Mexico Lion Hunt (See also Artwork), 1927-1928; (includes sketches) (Box 5, Folder 33)
  - Notebooks, 1950-1959, 1971, undated; (4 folders) (Box 5, Folder 34-37)
  - Biographical, Historical, Nature, and Art Writing, undated (Box 5, Folder 38)
  - Notes on Animals and Artwork, 1972, undated (Box 5, Folder 39)
  - Notes by and about Walt Kuhn, 1965, undated (Box 5, Folder 40)
  - Private Collectors of Bransom, 1965, 1969, undated (Box 5, Folder 41)
  - Jackson Hole People and Dude Ranches, 1973, undated (Box 5, Folder 42)
  - Miscellaneous Notes, 1972, 1973, undated; (See also OV 12) (Box 5, Folder 43)
  - Poems by Friends and Admirers, 1970, undated; (not scanned) (Box 5, Folder 44)
  - H.C. Pitz Inventory, undated; (photocopy, not scanned) (Box 5, Folder 45)
  - Oversized Miscellaneous Notes (See Box 5, f42) (Box 12 (OV))
- Personal Business Records, circa 1912-1981; Series 4; 0.3 Linear feet Box 5
  This series includes records relating to Bransom's illustration and advertising clients, galleries where he exhibited, other Bransom projects, bibliographies and inventories of Bransom's artwork, and records of projects of family members. Arrangement is alphabetical by gallery or business entity, with special subjects placed at the end of the series. Types of records include correspondence, receipts, lists, notes, contracts, pamphlets, and brochures.
  Gallery and illustration client records document exhibitions, consignments, and sales of Bransom's artwork. The files for Teton Artists Associated also contain Bransom's designs for brochures and advertisements, proofs of printed materials, a contract, and lists of students. The file for Northwest Schools contains a contract for the production of an instructional book on animal drawing by Bransom, as well as correspondence related to the project. For a copy of that publication, see Printed Materials.
  Also found are bibliographies compiled by Seth Mattingly and Helen Ireland Hays, and an artwork inventory compiled by Mario Cesar Romero after Bransom's death. Drafts of Mattingly's bibliographies are found with his correspondence in Series 1. Additional correspondence related to Bransom's business activities, including magazine and book illustrations, exhibitions, and other business with entities listed in this series can also be found in the Correspondence series. Exhibition Catalogs and other printed materials related to exhibitions can be found in Printed Materials.
  - Abercrombie and Fitch, 1939-1941, 1967 (Box 5, Folder 46)
  - Morris L. Appleman, Denver Exhibition, 1950 (Box 5, Folder 47)
  - Artists Day at Christmas Sales for the Blind, 1954-1966, undated (Box 5, Folder 48)
  - Charles Scribner's Sons, 1931-1937 (Box 5, Folder 49)
  - General Store Gallery, 1970-1971, undated (Box 5, Folder 50)
  - Grand Central Galleries, 1966-1973, undated (Box 5, Folder 51)
  - Hawley Advertising Company, 1933 (Box 5, Folder 52)
  - Lord and Thomas Advertising, 1932 (Box 5, Folder 53)
  - Northwest Schools, Inc., 1961-1962 (Box 5, Folder 54)
  - Royal Ontario Museum, 1975-1976 (Box 5, Folder 55)
  - Seagram Distillers Company, 1956-1962, undated (Box 5, Folder 56)
  - Society of Illustrators, 1942 (Box 5, Folder 57)
  - Teton Artists Associated, 1958-1962, undated; (2 folders) (Box 5, Folder 58-59)
  - The Toronto Star, 1945 (Box 5, Folder 60)
  - Woodmere Art Gallery, 1962-1964, undated (Box 5, Folder 61)
  - Notices of Receipt for Artwork, 1925, 1964-1979, undated (Box 5, Folder 62)
    (Contains records from Arden Studios, Inc., The James Ford Bell Museum of Natural History in Minnesota, the Fulton County Museum, and the Brandywine River Museum)
  - Miscellaneous Consignments and Sales, 1942-1980, undated (Box 5, Folder 63)
  - Miscellaneous Receipts, 1912-1978 (Box 5, Folder 64)
  - Personal Financial Records, 1924, 1949, 1962-1972 (Box 5, Folder 65)
  - Grace Bransom's Doll Business, 1953, undated (Box 5, Folder 66)
  - Harry Bond's Invention, 1934 (Box 5, Folder 67)
  - Bibliography of Illustrations, 1980, undated (Box 5, Folder 68)
  - Bibliography and Artwork Inventory, 1980-1981 (Box 5, Folder 69)
  - Artwork Inventory Project Notes, undated (Box 5, Folder 70)
  - Artwork Inventory, circa 1981; (7 folders) (Box 6, Folder 1-7)
- Printed Materials, circa 1905-1985; Series 5; 1.5 Linear feet Boxes 6-7, OV 12
  This series includes catalogs and announcements for exhibitions; reproductions of Bransom illustrations and cartoons from magazines, newspapers, and calendars; newspaper and magazine articles about Bransom and others; programs from musical events in which Bransom performed; newsletters, brochures, membership directories, mailings, and invitations from organizations in which Bransom was involved; pamphlets and other printed matter about Jack London and other people known to Bransom; and a copy of Bransom's art technique book, Animal Drawing.
  Catalogs are for individual and group exhibitions of Bransom's artwork, some of which are annotated with prices and other information. Printed price lists, press releases, and invitations are also found. Selected catalogs of exhibitions by Walt Kuhn and his pupil, Lily Cushing are filed under their names.
  Many of Bransom's illustrations for magazine stories are also found, including stories by writers Albert Payson Terhune and Jim Corbett. An early newspaper cartoon series by Bransom called "News From Bugville" is represented here by over 200 printed copies of cartoons. An original drawing from Bransom's cartoon series is found in Artwork.
  Clippings include biographies, reviews of exhibitions, book reviews for books illustrated by Bransom, obituaries, and other news related to Bransom and his friends. Additional clippings are found in Scrapbooks, and scattered clippings are found in Correspondence.
  Printed material related to organizations ranges from a single item to long runs of newsletters or catalogs, with occasional annotations by Bransom and others. The Salmagundi Club and the Society of Animal Artists have the widest range of materials, including newsletters, announcements, exhibition documentation, membership directories, and other mailings. See also Personal Business Records for original records of Bransom's transactions with some of the organizations listed here.
  - Exhibition Announcements and Catalogs (Box 6)
    - Paul Bransom, 1929-1983, undated; (5 folders, including duplicates) (Box 6, Folder 8-12)
      Existence and Location of Copies note
      partially scanned
    - Lily Cushing, 1947; (not scanned) (Box 6, Folder 13)
    - Walt Kuhn, 1927-1962, undated; (2 folders; not scanned) (Box 6, Folder 14-15)
  - Illustrations by Paul Bransom, 1925-1939; (See also OV 12) (Box 6, Folder 16)
  - Illustrations by Paul Bransom, 1942-1979; (See also OV 12) (Box 6, Folder 17)
  - Illustrations by Paul Bransom, undated; (See also OV 12) (Box 6, Folder 18)
  - Illustrations by Paul Bransom, Printers' Proofs, 1925, undated; (See also OV 12) (Box 6, Folder 19)
  - Reproductions of Artwork by Other Artists, undated; (See also OV 12; not scanned) (Box 6, Folder 20)
  - Bugs in Bugville and Other Cartoons by Paul Bransom, 1905-1909, undated; (6 folders) (Box 6, Folder 21-26)
  - Clippings about Paul Bransom, 1921-1929; (See also OV 12) (Box 6, Folder 27)
  - Clippings about Paul Bransom, 1935-1948; (See also OV 12) (Box 6, Folder 28)
  - Clippings about Paul Bransom, 1950-1969; (See also OV 12) (Box 6, Folder 29)
  - Clippings about Paul Bransom, 1970-1985; (See also OV 12) (Box 6, Folder 30)
  - Clippings about Paul Bransom, undated (Box 6, Folder 31)
  - Clippings about Paul Bransom, Duplicates, 1947-1948, 1967; (not scanned) (Box 6, Folder 32)
  - Clippings about Walt Kuhn, 1920-1962, undated; (not scanned) (Box 6, Folder 33)
  - Clippings about Other Artists and Friends of Paul Bransom, 1965-1976, undated; (not scanned) (Box 6, Folder 34)
  - Music Concerts and Recitals, 1908 (Box 6, Folder 35)
  - Organizations, (not scanned) (Box 6)
    - Artists' Fellowship, Inc., 1974-1977 (Box 6, Folder 36)
    - American Artists Professional League, 1962-1978; (2 folders) (Box 6, Folder 37-38)
    - American Watercolor Society, 1959-1978; (3 folders) (Box 6, Folder 39-41)
    - Dutch Treat Club, 1972-1979 (Box 6, Folder 42)
    - Grand Central Art Galleries, 1965-1975 (Box 7, Folder 1-5)
    - Jackson Hole Fine Arts Foundation, 1962, undated (Box 7, Folder 6)
    - New York Water Color Club, 1928 (Box 7, Folder 7)
    - Salmagundi Club, 1950-1985, undated (Box 7, Folder 8-11)
    - Society of Animal Artists, 1962-1985, undated (Box 7, Folder 12-14)
    - Sportsman's Edge, Ltd., 1977-1979; (3 folders) (Box 7, Folder 15-17)
    - Miscellaneous Organizations, 1951-1981, undated (Box 7, Folder 18)
      (Includes materials related to Bear Paw Ranch; the Junior Literary Guild; the Burroughs Nature Study Club; The Eccentric Club of Gloversville, NY; the National Advertising Art Center, Inc.; the National Amateur Art Festival; the National Society of Arts and Letters; Weber State College; the Boone and Crockett Club; and the International Platform Association)
  - People, (not scanned) (Box 7)
    - Jack London, undated (Box 7, Folder 19)
    - Other Artists and Friends, 1947-1976, undated (Box 7, Folder 20)
  - Publications (Box 7)
    - Animal Drawing by Paul Bransom, undated; (See OV 12) (Box 7, Folder 21)
    - "Story of the Armory Show" by Walt Kuhn, 1938; (not scanned) (Box 7, Folder 22)
  - Oversized Printed Material, (See Box 6, f16-20, 27-30; and Box 7, f21) (Box 12)
- Photographs, circa 1885-1976; Series 6; 1.3 Linear feet Boxes 7-8, 10
  This series includes photographs depicting Bransom, his family, other artists, pets and other animals, homes and studios, landscapes, trips, events, and works of art. Many of the photographs in this series have identifications on them, some of which appear to have been made retrospectively by Bransom. Other identifications appear to be in the handwriting of his niece and heiress, Althea Bond; and Mario Cesar Romero, who signed his notes "MCR."
  Wherever possible, photographs which appear to have been taken and printed together have been filed together. Numerous photographs of Bransom painting and drawing are found in this series. See folder notes below and notes on the photographs themselves for additional information about content.
  The slide album has been re-housed for preservation, but the original arrangement of the slides in their sleeves has been preserved. Images in the slide album include Paul and Grace Bransom, their Canada Lake and Jackson Hole homes, landscapes in the Adirondack and Teton mountains, Bransoms' friends, Paul Bransom painting in the studio and outside, and nature photographs labeled "studies for paintings." Most of the slides are Kodachrome and have suffered very little fading.
  Additional photographs are found in Scrapbooks, and scattered photographs are found in Correspondence. See the series description for further details.
  - Portraits of Paul Bransom, 1940-1973, undated; (2 folders, including duplicates; See also Box 10) (Box 7, Folder 23-24)
  - Early Photographs of Paul Bransom (See also Scrapbooks), 1910, undated (Box 7, Folder 25-26)
    (Also pictured is Bransom's sister Mary)
  - Early Photographs of Grace Bond (Bransom), 1905, undated (Box 7, Folder 27)
    (Includes photograph taken in Bransom's 23rd St. Studio)
  - Bransom Family Photographs, 1885, 1920-1921, undated; (See also Box 10) (Box 7, Folder 28-29)
  - Bond Family Photographs, undated (Box 7, Folder 30)
  - Bransom Pets and Animals Used in Illustrations, undated (Box 7, Folder 31)
  - Bransom in Groups with Other Artists, 1904-1952, undated; (See also Box 10) (Box 7, Folder 32)
    (Among those identified are T.S. Sullivant, James Swinnerton, H.A. Magill, Marjorie Organ, T.S. Allen, Gus Mager, Lynn Bogue Hunt, Arthur Fuller, and Bob Kuhn)
  - Portraits of Artist Friends of Bransom, 1920-1971, undated (Box 7, Folder 33)
    (Pictured are Gus Mager, Walt Kuhn, Bill Scott, Bud Shannon, Charles Leon, Lynn Bogue Hunt, Raechell Scott, Joe Back, Clarence Tillenius)
  - Paul Bransom on Hunting Expeditions, 1926-1927 (Box 7, Folder 34)
    (Bransom pictured with E.H. Taylor and J. Frank Dobie)
  - Paul and Grace Bransom's Trip West, 1928 (Box 7, Folder 35)
    (Pictured are the Bransoms and Toby and Marion Vreeland)
  - Snapshots of Paul Bransom, Grace Bransom, and Others, circa 1910s-1963; (3 folders, including duplicates and negatives; see also Box 10) (Box 7, Folder 36-38)
  - Snapshots of Paul Bransom and Others, 1964-1976, undated (Box 7, Folder 39)
  - Homes and Studios of Paul Bransom (Box 7)
    See also Scrapbooks
    - Brookland, DC (Birthplace), undated (Box 7, Folder 40)
    - 23rd Street Studio, NYC, circa 1900s; (See Box 10) (Box 7, Folder 41)
    - Saratoga Springs, NY, circa 1914-1917 (Box 7, Folder 42)
    - Canada Lake, NY, 1918-1925, undated (Box 7, Folder 43)
      (Includes photo of Bransom painting in studio)
    - Canada Lake, NY, 1926-1929, undated; (5 folders, including duplicates and negatives) (Box 7, Folder 44-48)
      (Bransom and others pictured in first of five folders)
    - Canada Lake, NY, Black and White Series, 1930, undated; (5 folders; see also Box 10) (Box 7, Folder 49-53)
      (Includes photographs of garden sculpture by Leo Lentelli and a series of photographs by Herbert Lawson)
    - Canada Lake, NY, Color Series, undated (Box 7, Folder 54)
      (Bransoms pictured)
    - New York City Apartment, 1962, undated (Box 8, Folder 1)
    - Jackson Hole, Wyoming, 1948-1962 (Box 8, Folder 2)
      (Bransoms and others pictured)
  - Homes of Friends of Bransom, 1943, 1971, undated (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - Events (Box 8)
    - Artists Day at Christmas Sales for the Blind, 1953 (Box 8, Folder 4)
    - Teton Artists Associated Classes, 1959-1961, undated; (2 folders, including copies) (Box 8, Folder 5-6)
    - Society of Animal Artists Reception, circa 1960s (Box 8, Folder 7)
    - Weber State College Honorary Doctorate, 1974; (See also Box 10) (Box 8, Folder 8)
  - Unidentified People, 1959, 1976, undated (Box 8, Folder 9)
  - Unidentified Landscapes, undated (Box 8, Folder 10)
  - Miscellaneous Animal Photographs, 1968-1972, undated; (See also Box 10) (Box 8, Folder 11)
  - Slide Album, 1953-1967, undated; (5 folders) (Box 8, Folder 12-16)
    (People pictured in folders 2, 3 and 4)
  - Photograph Albums from 90th Birthday, 1975; (2 folders; not scanned) (Box 8, Folder 17-18)
  - Works of Art (Box 8)
    - By Bransom, Installation Views, 1962-1975, undated (Box 8, Folder 19)
    - By Bransom, 1948-1972, undated; (4 folders, including negatives; not scanned) (Box 8, Folder 20-23)
    - By Others, 1937-1976, undated; (See also Box 10; not scanned) (Box 8, Folder 24)
  - Oversized Photographs (See Box 7, f23, 30, 33, 39, 42, 53; and Box 8, f8, 11, 24) (Box 10 (sol))
- Scrapbooks, circa 1880s-1970s; Series 7; 0.5 Linear feet Boxes 8 and 11
  This series consists of two scrapbooks containing clippings, photographs, and exhibition announcements. Neither volume appears to have been made by Bransom himself, and both were part of the donation of Mario Cesar Romero, who had access to the Bransom estate while curating a retrospective exhibition of Bransom's artwork and creating the artwork inventory in Series 4.
  Volume I consists entirely of printed material, mostly clippings and one advertisement for a book illustrated by Bransom, The Argosy of Fables (1921). Clippings also include multiple obituaries. Many of the items in Volume I are duplicated in the Printed Material series.
  Volume II contains exhibition announcements (1929-1931), clippings (1920s-1970s), and photographs (circa 1886-1970). Original photographs have been removed from the scrapbook as a preservation measure and to provide access to Bransom's notes on the backs of photographs. Pages containing the removed photographs have been replaced by photocopies reflecting their original arrangement in the scrapbook. Many of the photographs found in this scrapbook are not found elsewhere in Bransom's papers. Identifications on the scrapbook pages were made by Mario Cesar Romero.
  - Volume I, undated (Box 8, Folder 25)
    (Clippings, 1906-1982)
  - Volume II, undated; (See Box 11) (Box 8, Folder 26)
    (Original scrapbook pages containing clippings, exhibition announcements, photographs, and newspaper cartoons dated circa 1886-1979)
  - Items Found Tucked Between Pages of Volume II, undated; (See also Box 11) (Box 8, Folder 27)